(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-26T21:09:56.870995",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
甘くって幸せなこと
Sweet and happy things...
隠し味何にしよう
What secret ingredient should I use?
純粋な乙女心
A pure maiden's heart,
甘い恋も絡めなくちゃ
Must be tangled with sweet love too!
切なさ重ねてミルフィーユ
Layering sorrow like a mille-feuille,
酸味も積み上げたタルト
A tart piled high with sourness too,
苦味もチョコレートケーキ？
Or maybe a bitter chocolate cake?
魔法かけた甘い奇跡
A sweet miracle cast with magic!
甘さを抑えてビターとか
Toning down the sweetness for bitterness,
ミルクなしのコーヒーとか
Or coffee without any milk,
甘いだけじゃ大人になれないの？
"Can't you become an adult with just sweets?"
そんなの絶対に絶対に嫌だ嫌だ嫌だ！
There's no way, no way, I hate that, I hate that!
ねえあげようか 甘い罠
Hey, shall I give you a sweet trap?
ほら虜にしてあげる
Look, I'll make you my captive!
そんな魔法かけるから
Since I'll cast such magic on you,
ちょっとだけ待たせたげるわ
I'll make you wait just a little bit.
たった一口が足りなくて
Just one bite isn't enough,
赤いイチゴみたい意地張って
Acting stubborn like a red strawberry,
甘いところなんて見せないわ
I won't show you my sweet side.
完璧に作るもん一人でもでもでも！
I'll make it perfectly, even all alone!
今日は紫シオン生誕祭ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to my birthday live!
最後まで目を離さず楽しんでいってねー！
Please enjoy it all the way to the end!
スウィーティ スウィーティ スウィーティマジック
Sweety, sweety, sweety magic!
スウィーティ スウィーティ スウィーティイェイイェイ
Sweety, sweety, sweety, yeah yeah!
スウィーティ スウィーティ スウィーティマジック
Sweety, sweety, sweety magic!
スウィーティ スウィーティ スウィーティ
Sweety, sweety, sweety...
たった一口が足りなくて
Just one bite isn't enough,
赤いイチゴみたい意地張って
Acting stubborn like a red strawberry,
甘いところなんて見せないわ
I won't show you my sweet side.
完璧に作るもん一人でもでもでも！
I'll make it perfectly, even all alone!
隠し味恋心
The secret ingredient is love,
苦味とか酸味とか
Bitterness or sourness,
そういうのもたまにはいいわ
Sometimes those are nice too.
意地っ張りでワガママな
Stubborn and selfish,
そんな甘い魔法使い
That's a sweet magic user!
苦味とか酸味とか
Bitterness or sourness,
そういうのもたまにはいいわ
Sometimes those are nice too.
意地っ張りでワガママな
Stubborn and selfish,
そんな甘い魔法使い
That's a sweet magic user!
スウィーティマジック
Sweety magic!
はーい、みんなー！見えてるー？
Hi, everyone! Can you see me?
今日は生誕祭ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live today!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、というわけで1曲目はスイートマジックでした！
So, the first song was "Sweet Magic"!
イェーイ！どうだった？
Yay! How was it?
1曲目だからね、可愛い歌を歌おうと思って
Since it's the first song, I wanted to sing a cute one
盛り上がるように可愛い歌を選んでみました。
to get everyone hyped and chose a cute song.
ダンスもね、実はこっそり頑張ってたのと
And I actually secretly worked hard on the dancing too,
かわいかった？どうだった？みんなどうだった？
was it cute? How was it, everyone?
え、よかった？本当？よかった！やったー！
Eh, was it good? Really? It was good! Yay!
今日はですね、ダンスがねよく見えるように見てください。
Today, please watch so you can see the dancing well.
アイドル仕様… ちょっと
Idol spec... Wait,
身長みたいなの、骨盤サポートしか思い浮かばん
for height-like things, I can only think of pelvic support.
どう？みて？ぴーす、ぴ、うさぎ？うさぎ？ぴょんぴょん
How is it? Look? Peace, rabbit? Pyon pyon!
はい、みんな写真撮ってね、あの
Yes, everyone take pictures, um...
あ、そうだ、写真撮って、ハッシュタグ紫シオン
Oh right, take pictures and use the hashtag Murasaki Shion
生誕祭2021でツイートしてください、こっちかな？ツイートしてねいっぱい
birthday live 2021 to tweet, this way? Tweet a lot!
いっぱい感想とかね写真とか待っておりますので、え、どうそ
I'm waiting for lots of photos and impressions, so please
トレンド入りを目指して頑張っていこうと思います。
let's work hard to get into trending.
ツイートしてね、いっぱい。あ、そうだ、そんなことよりそんなことって言うのもあれだけど
Tweet a lot! Oh right, more importantly than that—
そんなことよりだよ そんなことよりみんな気になってると思うけど
more importantly, everyone's probably curious about this, but
じゃじゃーん！このステージ、すごくないでしょ？
Ta-da! Isn't this stage amazing?
めちゃめちゃ綺麗だよね、ほら見てみんな、星空だよ！
It's so pretty, look everyone, it's a starry sky!
満天の星空みたいなキラキラしてて、めちゃめちゃ綺麗！
Like a starry night sky, sparkling and so pretty!
今回のためにね、今回のライブのために作ってもらいました。いや、本当にね、素晴らしいセンス…
Man, truly, wonderful sense...
ど、ど、抜群のセンス！あ、ほら、見てよみんなだよ、あれシオンこだよ、シオンこ！
An outstanding sense! Oh, look everyone, Shion-ko!
ね、ぴちぴちしてて、マジ生きてるからね！あとね、センディガンちゃん？センディガンちゃんと
Plump and lively, she's seriously alive! And Cendigan-chan too!
月城がね、空に浮いてまーす！めちゃめちゃ綺麗！
Tsukishiro are floating in the sky! So pretty!
みんな目ぴちぴちしてんじゃん、かわいいね！何しゃ、可愛い、可愛いこぶってんじゃねえよ！ほん、シオンが一番可愛いから！
Everyone's blinking, so cute! Don't act cute! Shion is the cutest!
はい、というわけで今回のために作ってもらいました。いやめちゃめちゃ可愛い。
Yes, so they made this for this occasion. Super cute!
シオン的にはね、空がねキラキラしてて超可愛い！あとですね、ロゴもね今回のために作ってもらいました。
For Shion, the sky is sparkling and super cute! And the logo too!
そう、紫シオン生誕祭ライブって書いてあって、真ん中になんて書いてある？紫シオンバースデーライブ2021！って書いてあります(笑)。可愛いでしょう、めちゃめちゃ素敵でしょ？可愛いでしょう？そう。
It says "Murasaki Shion Birthday Live 2021!" Isn't it cute?
はい、というわけで今日はですね、シオンの誕生日ということで、やまあね、見てのとおりね誰もいないからね、本当にこの、この広いステージには1人ででお祝いしていこうかなと思います。いえーい！
Today is Shion's birthday, and I'll celebrate all alone on this big stage. Yay!
今ね1人だからって、1人じゃ話しにくいしね、盛り上がっていこうと思います。(笑)
Even all alone, it's hard to talk, but let's get hyped!
はい、というわけでね、やっぱり誕生日といえばよ、みんな誕生日といえば何ですか？ケーキ！はい、そしてクラッカーですよね、やっぱクラッカー。
Speaking of birthdays, what do you think of? Cake! And crackers!
あの、あれ、ハンズで買った、百均で売ってるハンズ。え、というわけでシオンね、これ買ってきたんだよね、実質、ちょっと持って、持ってこよ。
Bought at a 100-yen shop. Shion bought this, so let me go get it.
じゃじゃーん！ほら、買ってきた！見て、準備万端だからね、誕生日楽しむ準備は満、満点、満点。満点満点、どっちか分かんないけど(笑)
Ta-da! Look, preparations to enjoy my birthday are full marks!
はい、というわけで、じゃあみんなでお祝いしていこうかなー！いくよみんな！誕生日おめでとうって言ってね。シオンが誕生日おめでとうって言ったら、みんなおめでとうって言うんだよ、いくよ？
Let's celebrate together! Say "Happy birthday" when I say it, okay?
せーの！誕生日おめでとうー！
Ready, set! Happy birthday!
パーン！うぇーーい！誕生日！
Pop! Woohoo! Birthday!
もう一回！おめでとう！
One more time! Congratulations!
おめでとう、おめでとう！イェーイ！
Congratulations, congratulations! Yay!
みんなにね、ほら、紙、紙のね、あの、紙吹雪をプレゼントしよう。おめでとう！
Let's present everyone with paper confetti. Congratulations!
イェーイ！はい、というわけでみんな、シオンの誕生日、紙しかさっきから出てこないな、さっきからさっきから出てこないな、もういいや、それは。
Only paper has been coming out since earlier... oh well!
はい、せっかくだからね、やっぱせっかくだから誕生日って言ったらさ、さっきさ二個出したけどさ、クラッカーとケーキでしょ？いやケーキとかさその
Speaking of birthdays, earlier I brought out crackers and cake, right?
ケーキさ、ちょっと入ったりしないか
Won't cake, like, fit in a bit?
おー！
Whoa!
ヤセのケーキだ
It's a skinny cake!
こんなとこにヤセのケーキが現れた
A skinny cake appeared in a place like this!
えっとえっと写真撮る、写真
Um, um, take a picture, a picture!
インスタ映え写真撮って、インスタ映え写真ほら
Take an Insta-worthy picture, look, an Insta picture!
あ、いいじゃん、いいじゃん
Ah, that's good, that's good!
ほら、いえー、ほら、はい
Look, look, yay, look, ready!
はい、チーズ
Cheese!
え、やった、ほら1才かな、これは
Yay, look, is this 1 year old?
これ1才なのかな？
Is this 1 year old?
食べたいな、ケーキ
I want to eat it, the cake.
食べちゃおうか
Shall I eat it?
あ、こんなとこにね、フォーク持って、ちょっと食べちゃお
Ah, with a fork right here, let's eat a bit.
うめえな、やっぱケーキ
It's so good, cake after all!
みんなも、あーげない
Do you guys want some? Not givin' any!
全部完食すっからね、これホールケーキ
I'm eating the whole thing, you know, this whole cake.
でもちんみんなも食べていいよ、ほら
But you guys can eat it too, look...
あげないけど
Though I'm not giving any!
全然あげないけど
I'm really not giving any!
ママに、見せてあげる、見せてあげる
Mommy, I'll show you, I'll show you!
断面とかね、ケーキの断面とか
The cross section, like, the cake's cross section.
いやあ、おいしいなやっぱ、ショートケーキ
Man, cake is so good after all, shortcake!
いちごがね、いちごが美味しいからね、生クリーム好きだけど
Strawberries are good, strawberries are delicious, though I like whipped cream too.
生クリームも好きだけどね
I like whipped cream too, though.
あ、もう一個しかないよ
Ah, there's only one left!
あ、なくなった！完食、ホールケーキ完食
Ah, it's gone! Finished, the whole cake is finished.
ほら、みんな食べました、証拠
Look, everyone, we ate it, proof!
食べました証拠、証拠写真
Proof we ate it, a photo as proof.
はーい、いや満足だな、今日の誕生日もこれで大満足
Ah, man, I'm satisfied. Today's birthday is super satisfying with this!
えっと、そろそろ終わろうかなそろそろ配信、大満足したしね
Um, I guess I'll end the stream soon, since I'm super satisfied.
いやでもな、一人で楽しみすぎでさ、やっぱ、せっかくだからさ、誰かにバッてほしいよね
But you know, I enjoyed it too much by myself, so since it's a special occasion, I want someone to pop in!
1人で、1人でもいいんだけどね、いいんだけどさ、せっかくだならさ、誰か来てくんないかな
Alone, being alone is fine too, but since it's a special occasion, won't someone come visit?
暇そうな人探してくるか、ちょっと暇そうな人探してくるわみんな
Shall I go look for someone free? I'll go look for someone free, everyone!
ちょっと待っててここね、見てくるちょっとそこへ、ちょっと待って行ってくるわ！
Wait here, okay? Go check over there... Wait, I'll go check!
みんなー、暇な人連れてきたよー！
Everyone! I brought someone who was free!
暇だけじゃないから！
I'm not just free!
暇だけじゃねえ！
Not just free!
船長、でもさ、船長さん、めっちゃ可愛いからさ！
Captain! But Captain, you're super cute, so!
ね、めっちゃ可愛いからさ、一緒にさ歌お？
Hey, you're super cute, so let's sing together!
うん、歌う！
Yeah, let's sing!
マリンちゃんと歌う！一緒にターンね！
Sing with Marine-chan! Let's spin together!
「好き」って言って 「好き」って言って
Tell me you love me, tell me you love me,
他に何もいらないから
as there is nothing else for me that I need.
ねえ 「好き」って言って
Hey, tell me you love me,
忘れないように 君以外はいらないから
so I'll never forget, as I don't need anyone else but you.
おじゃま虫
Ojamamushi
君の声が好きなんだす
This voice that you own, I really love your voice.
君の放つ言葉すべて
Every word you have said, every single word,
漏らすことなく聞きたいんだ とりあえずは 録音しよう
I don't want to miss even just a single word, simply putting it, we should both start recording.
君の顔が好きなんだす
This face that you own, I really love your face.
笑う顔も照れた顔も
Your smiling face and your embarrassed face too,
そのすべてを見たいんだす
I want to see every single expression.
余すことなく君を撮ろう
I will catch all of them in my memory.
あわよくばシワシワになるまで 死ぬ時もメロメロでいるから
I hope we can stay together until we're both wrinkly, I'll surely love you so much until the day I die.
君の夢をすべて叶えたいんだ おじゃま虫僕の夢なんだ
I want to fulfill every single one of your dreams, I dream to be that sticky bug that's right by your side.
「好き」って言って 「好き」って言って
Tell me you love me, tell me you love me,
他に何もいらないから
as there is nothing else for me that I need.
ねえ 「好き」って言って
Hey, tell me you love me,
忘れないように 君以外はいらないから
so I'll never forget, as I don't need anyone else but you.
君の胸が好きなんだす
This chest that you own, I really love your chest.
小さすぎず 大きすぎず まさに理想完璧だけど
It is not too small, and it is not too large, it's exactly ideal, maybe even perfect.
君は「まだ、足りない。」と言う
But you have told me, "No, it's still lacking."
足りないとゆうの
Saying that it's still not enough.
さようならはまた君に会うため
Saying goodbye is just to meet you again.
おやすみは明日のおはようのため
And goodnight is for tomorrow's good morning.
君の日々を少し邪魔したいんだ
I want to intrude on your days just a little bit.
これからもどうかよろしくね
Please continue to take care of me from now on.
「好き」って言って 「好き」って言って
Say you love me, say you love me,
他に何もいらないから
because I don't need anything else.
「好き」って言って 忘れないように
Say you love me, so I won't forget,
君以外はいらないから
because I don't need anyone but you.
大好き
I love you so much,
大々好き
I love you so, so much,
超好き
I super love you,
もう分かんないくらい好き
so much I don't even understand anymore.
先っちょだけだから この思いを許させてよ
It's just the tip, so please forgive this feeling.
「好き」って言って 「好き」って言って
Say you love me, say you love me,
他に何もいらないとかはやだ
I hate it when you say you don't need anything else.
「好き」って言って あわよくばやっぱ
Say you love me, and if possible,
君自身が欲しいんです
I actually want you yourself.
楽しかったね！
That was fun!
楽しかったね、船長！
That was fun, Captain!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
じゃあさ、猫ちゃんのポーズしよう！
Let's do a cat pose!
行くよ？せーの！
Ready? One, two!
ちょっと待って待って、もう一回！
Wait, wait, one more time!
かわいいポーズでしょ？
That's a cute pose, right?
じゃあ次はうさぎさんのポーズしよう！
Next let's do a rabbit pose!
せーの！
Ready, go!
船長、船長ちょっと…
Captain, Captain, wait...
なんかかわいいこと、お尻ポンポン出てきてるよ
Your butt is popping out in a cute way.
お尻ポンポンじゃないもん！
It is not popping out!
きつい！きついよ！
That's harsh! That's harsh!
しょうたん、髪が可愛いから呼んでくれたんでしょ？
Shion-tan, you invited me because my hair is cute, right?
おばさんじゃんこんなの！
This looks like an old lady!
かわいいって言ってくれたよね！？
You told me it was cute, didn't you!?
言ってくれたじゃん！なのに何経って、おばさんじゃん！
You did! But what is this, an old lady?!
次のゲストに行く気…マリを捨てて可愛いマリを捨てる気！？
You're planning to go to the next guest... discarding cute Marine?!
船長、ごめんね。
Captain, I'm sorry.
しょう、行かなきゃ。
Shion, I have to go.
船長はさ、可愛いけど他にも可愛い女がいるんだ。
Captain, you're cute, but there are other cute girls too.
じゃあね。
See ya.
白い雪のプリンセスは 作詞・作曲 のぼる↑
[Title: Shiroi Yuki no Princess wa / Music & Lyrics: Noboru↑]
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん 世界で一番可愛いのは
Mirror, mirror on the wall, who is the cutest in the world?
やめてよ とげのような視線迫る
Stop it, thorny gazes close in on me.
優しいふりした彼女が 素敵な晩餐もてなした
The seemingly kind girl served a wonderful dinner,
そっと口に含む微笑み
smiling as she took a bite.
薄れていく意識の中で 夢を見てる
Dozing off in fading consciousness, dreaming
いつかのおとぎ話
of a fairytale from long ago.
時が止まる お願いKISSで
Time stops, please wake me up
目を覚まして欲しいの
with a kiss.
白い棺から 連れ出すように
Like leading me out of a white coffin,
突き刺す憎しみは ドラマチックな事情
piercing hatred is a dramatic affair.
祈っても 王子様は まだ来ない
Even if I pray, the prince hasn't come yet.
真っ白い棺から連れ出して
Please lead me out of the pure white coffin.
鏡よ鏡 鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror on the wall,
突き刺さる 憎しみは
The piercing hatred
ドラマチックな事情を
is a dramatic circumstance.
祈っても 君は まだ 来ない
Even if I pray, you're still not here.
鏡よ鏡 鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror on the wall,
ネクタイ任せや 頬に挨拶するから
Fixing your necktie, greeting you on the cheek,
寵愛を買われてしまった
My affection was bought.
7人の小人はいるけど
The seven dwarves are here, but
助ける素振り 知らんぷりね そっと首を掴まれ 笑み
acting like they'll help, playing dumb, my throat gently grabbed with a smile...
一粒の涙さえも拭えなくて
Unable to wipe away even a single tear,
呼吸もままならない 視界失った
unable to breathe properly, I lost my sight.
消えそうだから 早く駆けて欲しいの
I'm about to fade, so I want you to run to me quickly,
訳は聞かないで 応えられない
don't ask why, I can't answer.
望まない憎まれは 深い愛の二乗
Unwanted hatred is the square of deep love,
もうすぐでいなくなってしまうのかな
will I be gone very soon?
途切れてく命の音
The sound of life fading away.
毒リンゴを食った少女のように 眠りにつく
Sleeping like a girl who ate a poisonous apple,
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss,
胸の中の声 届きますか
does the voice inside my chest reach you?
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss,
胸の中の声届きますか
does the voice inside my chest reach you?
階段を上ったらドアを開けるだけで見つかるよ
If you go up the stairs and open the door, you'll find it.
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss,
白い棺から 連れ出すように
so you can lead me out of the white coffin.
突き刺さる憎しみは ドラマチックな事情を
The piercing hatred is a dramatic circumstance,
祈っても 王子様は まだ 来ない
Even if I pray, my prince is still not here.
鏡よ鏡 鏡さん 消えてしまおう
Mirror, mirror, mirror on the wall, I'll fade away.
今日来てくれてありがとう！
Thanks for coming today!
当たり前でしょ、ありがとう！
Of course, thank you!
シオン先輩の生誕祭ライブ、おめでとう！
Happy birthday to Shion-senpai's live!
ありがとう！嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
いやてかさ、二人で3Dコラボってこれ初めてべこじゃないの？
Wait, isn't this our first 3D collab ever, Pekora?
え、確かに！今まで大人数の3Dとかもないよね、たぶん。
Eh, true! Up until now, there hasn't even been a group 3D, probably.
いや、そうってことだね、なんか こうやって3Dないよね。
Yeah, exactly, like we don't do 3D like this.
うん、そうそうライブ二人ともないしね3Dね。
Yeah, live shows, the two of us didn't even have 3D together.
なんか、なんで仲良くなったんだっけ、今まで。
How did we become close in the first place?
え、なんで仲良くなったっけ？できたじゃん！
Eh, why did we become close? We just did!
なんて、なんで、忘れないでよ！他の人とやってんじゃん！
Wait, why, don't forget! You do stuff with other people too!
ちょっと、え、でも、いいじゃん！どうして今日呼んでくれたの？
Wait, eh, but, it's fine! Why did you invite me today?
どうして今日呼んでくれたの？いいじゃん！
Why did you invite me today? It's fine!
そういうことじゃなくてさ、でもさ普段ゲーム配信とかではコラボとかちょこちょこしてたもんね？
That's not what I mean, but we used to collab in game streams and stuff now and then, right?
そしてだし、でも歌うの初めてだよね、二人で。
And also, this is our first time singing together, right?
そう！だからさ、シオン先輩とデュエットできてぺこらすごい嬉しかったぺこで。
Yeah! So Pekora was super happy to duet with Shion-senpai.
え、嬉しかったよ、ありがとうね！
Eh, I was happy too, thank you!
でもゲームはさ、あるね。最初のコラボって何だっけ？
But for games, yeah. What was our very first collab?
ちょっと待って、忘れたぺこなすか？
Wait a second, did you forget, pekona?
え、マジで？みんな、ちょっと待ってください、この方。
Eh, seriously? Everyone, please wait a minute, this person...
この方忘れてるよ、覚えているよ！
This person forgot, she remembers!
じゃあ言ってみなさいよ、あんたなんだか言ってみなさいよ、ぺこら覚えているから。
Then try saying it, say what it was, since Pekora remembers.
え、え、あの、あれあれあれ、あの、あのなんかホラーゲームっていったじゃん、ホラーゲーム。
Eh, um, that, that, that horror game we played!
皆さんこのマリオカートどうにかしてもらっていいですか？
Everyone, can someone please do something about this Mario Kart?
間違えた 間違えた 間違えた
I messed up, I messed up!
何何？隠れ家のやつ、隠れ家リムのやつ
What, what? The hideout Lim one, the hideout Lim one.
それは、それはるちゃんとり、ぺこーらとしおんちゃん三人…
That's— wait, that's Ru-chan and Ri— Pekora and Shion-chan, three people...
二人だよ！二人にあれぺこだよ。
Two people! That was Pekora.
なんか、るーちゃんですよ、るー
Like, it was Ru-chan, Ru—
え？ ちょっと待って待って！
Huh? Wait, wait, wait!
あ、かった！かった！マリオカート？ そうそうそう！そうだよね！
Ah, won! Won! Mario Kart? Yeah, yeah, yeah! That's right!
ちょっと、どのぺこだよ！喉を潰しちゃったぺこじゃん！
Wait, which Pekora is that?! You totally wrecked your throat!
いやでも、マリオカートめっちゃ前じゃない？
Well, but wasn't Mario Kart way back?
え、そうそう！めっちゃ前！っていうかむしろごめんぺこだけど、ペコラもそれが最初かわかんない。
Yeah, yeah! Way back! Or rather, sorry Pekora, but even Pekora doesn't know.
歌ってみたじゃねえよ！まっすぐいて！お前が体験して、すまんぺこだけど。
That wasn't a cover song! Straighten up! You experienced it, though sorry.
でも多分ね、ペコラの記憶的には、マリオカート、シオン先輩と、え、対決しようよ！みたいな感じ言って、やったやった！って言って。めっちゃ強かった印象で。
In Pekora's memory, for Mario Kart it was like, "Let's battle, Shion-senpai!" Super strong.
いやそうそう！ボコボコにした記憶がある。ボコボコにしたからわかんないけどね。
Yeah, yeah! I remember crushing her. Because I crushed her, I don't know.
そうされた気がする。え、てかさ、こうやって3Dコラボってさ、ちょつま、ありみ初めてぺこだから記念卒って言って、しないぺこです？
I feel like that's what happened. And for 3D collabs like this, since it's Ari-mi's first time as Pekora...
え、しようよ！ちょっとちょっと待って行こう！あれ？この端に寄ってる、端に？
Eh, let's do it! Wait, wait, let's go! Huh? Huddled over on this edge?
え、何何、何やるぺこ？ え、やっぱハートでしょ、ハート。
Eh, what are we doing, Pekora? Eh, heart of course, heart.
ま、アイドルたるものね！アイドルたるもの。じゃあいくよ、いく？せーの！
Well, as idols! As idols. Then here we go, ready? One, two, three!
はい！え？ちょっとちょっとちょっと！ねえ、二人でこれ、ごめん、ごめんごめん、ちょっと。
Yes! Huh? Wait, wait! Hey, the two of us— sorry, sorry, wait.
え、ちょっと！ぺこらの肩重いみたいな感じなんじゃん。せーの！はい！
Eh, wait! It's like Pekora's shoulder is heavy. Ready! One, two, three!
これでしょ？キャッチしてもらうよ、みんなに！ね、立って立って！ツイートしてツイート！
Like this? Have everyone catch it! Hey, stand up! Tweet it!
これどうよ？ え、いいじゃん、いいじゃん！どう？ぺこかわいい！ハートでしょ？
How's this? Eh, nice! How is it? Pekora is cute! Heart, right?
ハートハート！いいね！いいね！さっきこうやってる人いたけどね、こうやって。
Heart, heart! Nice! Some people were doing it like this earlier.
いやいやいや、こうやってやってる人もいましたけど。あ、じゃあ次、片思い。うざい！
No, no, there were people doing it too. Ah, next, unrequited love. Annoying!
え、片思い？え、そっか。うさぎみ、ういーの耳ついてて。いいでしょ、これ。揺れるぺこですから。
Eh, unrequited love? Ah, right. Ui's ears are attached. That's nice, sway-sway Pekora.
え、いいの？めっちゃ揺れてんじゃん！じゃ、なめらか、うさぎ飛びしよう、うさぎ飛び。え、いくぺこだよ？せーの！あ、ぺこ、かわいい！
Eh, is that okay? Swaying so much! Then, smooth, bunny hops! Ready? One, two, three!
いいね！これさ、最初ぺこなんか、大丈夫…あ、やばい、ちょっとごめんぺこ、見返えすかすかとか。
Nice! This, at first Pekora like... Ah, wait, sorry, reviewing it or something.
見ないであげてください！ちょっとNGですよ、NG！でもかわいいね！
Please don't watch! It's a bit NG, NG! But it's cute!
お前らなんかあるぺこ？ お前らなんだろう？
You guys got anything, Pekora? What could you guys have?
え、ちょっとさ、ぺこちゃんさ、ちょ、映ってよ、カメラさ！ 何？
Eh, wait, Pekora-chan, show yourself on camera! What?
ん？え、いぇい、いぇい、いぇい、いぇい、いぇい！ え、なんか映ってる？
Hm? Eh, yay, yay, yay, yay! Eh, is something showing?
映ってる！はい、鬼！いや、くそが！鬼！くそがきぺこじゃんマジで！
It's showing! Yes, oni! No, damn it! You're such a brat, seriously!
はいつのハイタッチだったんだよ！くそがきぺこじゃん！そんなの、よくテレビとかにいるわ！
What high five was that even from?! Such a brat! People like that are on TV!
じゃ、ペコラも…え、え？え？え？え？
Then, Pekora too... Eh, eh? Eh? Eh?
え、え？え？え？うさみみ… お、お、お、いいじゃんいいじゃん！うさぎ、うさぎになっちゃった！
Eh, eh? Usagi-mim... Oh, nice, nice! You became a rabbit!
いって！いって！かつ！いて、ちょっと待って！
Ouch! Ouch! Win! Ouch, wait a second!
いやでも本当にね、お誕生日ライブこれからも頑張ってほしいぺこなので、ペコラろそろ…お、いとましましょうか。
Well, since we want you to keep doing your best for your birthday live, Pekora will soon take her leave.
あ、うそなの？せっかく見てる…こんなから寂しいけど、またでも出てくれるぺこか？いいよ！あ、遊ぼうね！
Ah, is that a lie? Even though we're watching... It's lonely, will you appear again? Sure!
あ、遊ぼうぺこじゃ！バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Ah, let's play, Pekora! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
この世で造花より綺麗な花はないわ
There are no flowers in this world more beautiful than artificial ones,
何故ならば全ては嘘で作られている antipathy world
because everything is made of lies, an antipathy world.
絶望の雨はあたしの傘を突いて
The rain of despair pierces my umbrella,
湿る前髪とこころの裏面煩わしいわ
dampening my bangs and the backside of my heart, how annoying.
何時しか言葉の葉は疾うに枯れきって事の実はあたしに熟れている
Before I knew it, the leaves of words withered long ago, and the truth ripens within me.
鏡に映り嘘を描いて自らを見失った絵画
A painting reflecting in the mirror, painting lies, losing sight of oneself.
パッパッパラッパッパララッパッパ 謎々謎がいて遊びましょう
Pa-pa-pa-ra-pa-pa-ra-ra-pa-pa, let's play with riddles and puzzles.
タッタッタルッタッタルラルッタッタ 何故何故此処で踊っているのでしょう
Ta-t-ta-ru-t-ta-ru-ra-ru-t-ta, why, oh why are we dancing here?
簡単なことも解らないわ あたしって何だっけ
I don't even understand simple things, what was I again?
それすら夜の手に取り絆されて 愛のように消える
Even that is bound by the hands of the night, disappearing like love.
さようならまたねと呟いた
Muttering "farewell, see you again"
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ 嘘に絡みついている
Phony, phony, phony, entwined in lies.
この世で造花より綺麗な花はないわ
There are no flowers more beautiful than artificial ones in this world,
何故ならば全ては嘘で出来ている
Because everything is made of lies.
antipathy world,
An antipathy world,
何時しかそらの音がいやに鳴り合って
Before I knew it, the sounds of the sky clashed harshly,
色の目があなたを溶かしている
And eyes of color are melting you away.
鏡に映るあしたを欠いて
Missing the tomorrow reflected in the mirror,
誰しもが見間違えた虚像
A phantom that everyone mistook.
如何して愛なんてものに群がりそれを欲して生きるのだ
Why do people flock to things like love and live desiring them?
今日も泳いでいる夜の電車が通り過ぎていく
Today too, the night train swims by and passes us by.
踊り明かせよ パパッパパラッパパラッパッパッパ
Dance the night away, pa-pa-pa-parappa...
謎々かざして遊びましょう タタッカタッタラッタッタッカタッタ
Let's hold up riddles and play.
何故何故此処で痛むのでしょう
Why, oh why does it hurt right here?
簡単なことも解らないわ
I don't even understand simple things.
絶望の雨は止まないわ
The rain of despair never stops.
さようならも言えぬまま咽び泣いた
I sobbed without even being able to say goodbye.
嘘に絡まっているあした
A tomorrow entangled in lies.
簡単なことも解らないわ
I don't even understand simple things.
あしたって何だっけ
What was 'tomorrow' again?
それすら夜の手に取り縋って
Clinging even to that in the hands of night,
愛のように 消える さようならまたねと呟いた
Fading like love... I murmured, "Goodbye, see you later."
嘘に絡まっているあしたはフォニイ
A tomorrow entangled in lies, a phony.
造花だけが知っている秘密のフォニイ
A secret phony known only by artificial flowers.
裏路地の真ん中で馴れない景色と好かない匂いに
Right in the middle of a back alley, in unfamiliar scenery and unappealing scents,
私は覆われて染まっていくんでしょ
I am covered and dyed away, aren't I?
私は怖がりで知らないことには手を付けず
I'm a coward, never touching things I don't know,
誰かがやって来て毒味をするまで待っていた
Waiting until someone comes along to test the poison.
することは単純でマニュアル通りの生活を
What I do is simple: living life strictly by the manual,
来る日も淡々と過ごしていた
Passing each coming day monotonously.
そう、優しさ、優しさ、昨日の私もこうだった
Yes, kindness, kindness, yesterday's me was just like this.
そう、優しさ、優しさ、弱い音を吐いている
Yes, kindness, kindness, uttering weak complaints.
薄っぺらい人間です 一歩前に出るのはやめときます
I'm a shallow person, so I'll refrain from stepping forward.
絡まれたくないからさ
Because I don't want to get involved.
描いた理想像に現実味がないからさ
Because my envisioned ideal has no reality to it,
近づけないよう息ときます 明日も同じように過ごします
I hold my breath to keep distance, spending tomorrow just the same.
路地裏の真ん中でいつもの夕日を薄目で眺めて 胸の中で呟いた「いつまで続くんだろう」
Gazing squinted at the usual sunset in the back alley, I whispered inside my chest, "How long will this last?"
そう、優しさ、優しさ、昨日の夕飯これだった
Yes, kindness, kindness, yesterday's dinner was this.
そう、優しさ、優しさ、脆弱で切れが悪い
Yes, kindness, kindness, fragile and dull.
意気地なし人間です 一歩後ろに下がって逃げときます
I'm a spineless person, so I'll step back and run away.
目立ちたくなんかないからさ 描いた理想像に現実味がないからさ
Because I don't want to stand out, and my ideal lacks reality.
近づけないよう息ときます 明日も同じように過ごします
I hold my breath to keep distance, spending tomorrow just the same.
薄っぺらい人間です 一歩前に出るのはやめときます
I'm a shallow person, so I'll refrain from stepping forward.
絡まれたくないからさ
Because I don't want to get involved.
ため息ばっかでさ 吸う息足りないの
Just sighing all the time, running out of breath to inhale.
きっと 上手はいかないけどさ
Things surely won't go well, but...
試しにちゃんと生きてみよう
Let's try actually living properly for once.
はい、というわけで、その曲続けて2曲聴いてももらいました！どうだったでしょうか、みんな！
So, there you have it! I just sang two songs back-to-back! How did you all like them?
えー、1曲目はですね、フォニイ！
Umm, the first song was... "Phony"!
1曲目が弱音吐きでした。
The first song was "Yowanehaki."
はい、この曲を選んだ理由はですね、
Yes, the reason I chose this song is...
自分の中で2曲目が流行ってたからですね。
because this song was trending among us at the time.
ちょっとね、流行りに遅れてね、
I tend to be a bit late to trends,
フォニーが流行ってるタイミングよりあとに聴いてしまいます。
listening to songs like "Phony" long after they peak.
いろんな曲全部流行ってる曲
All those popular songs,
流行りに1歩遅れて
I'm always a step behind the trend.
1歩 後ろに差があって
Lagging a step behind!
はい、つーわけでみんなどうだったかな？
Alright, so how was it everyone?
よかった？よかったかな？
Was it good? Was it okay?
はい、つーわけでここからはですね、
Alright, from here on,
今その曲が2曲目終わったということで
now that two songs have finished,
またゲストパート！ゲストさんを呼んで一緒に歌いたいと思います。
it's the guest part! I'll invite a guest to sing along.
次のゲストを呼んでい、来ちゃおっかなー！
Shall I call out the next guest?
じゃあみんな行ってくるからちょっと待っててね。
Everyone wait for me, okay?
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
また始まった 忘れんぼう
It's started again, you forgetful one.
手帳の隅っこだって カレンダーにだって
Right in the corner of your planner, on the calendar,
マルしといたのに
even though I marked it down,
どうして怒ってるか おわかりですか
do you understand why I'm angry?
謝っても 許さないんだからね
Even if you apologize, I won't forgive you.
どこにでもあるような
Like something found anywhere,
どこにもないような
like something found nowhere,
シアワセ探しは まだ始まったばっか
our search for happiness has just begun.
楽しみにしてた プリンだって
Even the pudding I was looking forward to—
君に食べられる為に 生まれたわけじゃなかったのに な
it wasn't born just to be eaten by you, you know.
それ ちょっとだけ頂戴
"Just give me a little bit of that."
ねえ 一口だけ頂戴 なんて
"Hey, give me just a bite," or something like that.
あまりにも 都合が良すぎ じゃない の？
Isn't that a bit too convenient for you?
飽きちゃったらいらない
"If you get tired of it, you don't want it."
残しちゃったらごめんなさいって
Saying "Sorry if I left any."
…君のせいかしら？
...Is it your fault?
一体全体、私のことを どれくらい愛している？
How much do you love me, as a whole?
って 言葉じゃなくて 形式で 欲しい の です
I want it in actions, not just in words.
今日が 何の日か お 忘れ ですか
Did you forget what day today is?
でも 誕生日 なんて 言う の も ちょっと 癪 ね
Though saying it's my birthday is a bit annoying.
気付かないとか 誘いを断り不意 とか
Like not noticing, or unexpectedly turning down invitations,
幸せだった時を いちいち語る 前に
before talking on and on about when we were happy,
タバコやお酒は 控えるとか
cutting back on tobacco and alcohol,
明日から真面目にやるとか だらだら続いているじゃん！
starting to take things seriously from tomorrow—it's just dragging on!
それ ちょっとだけ頂戴
Just give me a little bit of that.
ねえ 一口だけ頂戴 なんて
Hey, give me just a bite, or something like that.
あまりにも 都合が良すぎじゃないの？
Isn't that a bit too convenient for you?
飽きちゃったらいらない
If you get tired of it, you don't want it.
残しちゃったらごめんなさいって
Saying "Sorry if I left any."
君のせいかしら 私のせいかしら
Is it your fault, or is it my fault?
一口だけ頂戴
Just give me a bite.
もう一口だけ頂戴なんて
Give me just one more bite, or something like that.
甘え上手って 罪なんじゃないの？
Isn't being good at acting spoiled a crime?
ちょっとだけ頂戴
Just give me a little bit.
ねえ 出来たら全部頂戴なんて
Hey, if you can, give me everything, or something like that.
君のせいかしら
Is it your fault?
私のせいかしら
Is it my fault?
やっぱ 君のせいかしら
I guess it's your fault after all.
シオン先輩お誕生日おめでとう！
Shion-senpai, happy birthday!
ありがとうございますルーちゃん！
Thank you so much, Rushia!
嬉しすぎるマジで。今日来てくれてありがとう本当に。
I'm genuinely so happy. Thank you so much for coming today.
えーこれってよかった！
I'm so glad!
ねえ本当に嬉しい。ありがとねシオン先輩呼んでくれて。
I'm really happy. Thanks for inviting me, Shion-senpai.
マジさっきまでさ、いや1人でさお誕生日パーティしてたんだよね実は。
Seriously, until just a moment ago, I was actually having a birthday party all by myself.
そうなの1人で？
Really, by yourself?
うん、そうだよ。
Yeah, exactly.
1番最初に1人でねケーキ食べほしちゃったもうごめんね残ってないんだ。
I ate the cake all by myself at the very beginning. Sorry, there's none left.
見てたよ！ケーキあの丸ごと食べたの。
I was watching! I saw you eat the whole cake!
どこに入っちゃったのかなって思って見てて。
I was wondering where it all went.
全部ここだよ、全部。
Right here, all of it!
なんか中にいっぱい入ってるホールケーキがね大きくして小さくしたんだ。
It's a whole cake packed inside, made big and then made small.
そうそう、あの踊ったらね、消化されたから。
Yeah, once I danced, it got digested.
いや本当におめでとう誕生日。
Seriously, happy birthday.
ありがとう！ルシアちゃんとさ前回さ、あのさ、ルシアちゃんの周年の
Thank you! Last time with Rushia-chan, for Rushia-chan's anniversary...
ねえ、一緒にやったの
Hey, we did one together...
そうだよね。7月の時にね、しおん先輩来てもらって
That's right. In July, Shion-senpai came over and...
あんま経ってないよね
It hasn't been that long, right?
どうだったっけ、4ヶ月ぐらいしか撮ってないね
Let's see, it's only been about four months since we filmed, right?
そうだよね
That's right.
え、じゃあ、あの、えでもさ、二人でこうやって歌うのはさ、2回、2回しかないよね、まだこれで。
Um, then, well, but, you know, singing together like this, we've only done it twice, right, so far?
あ、そうだ。そうだよね。2回目だ。
Ah, that's right. That's right. It's the second time.
いや嬉しいマジで、もう
I'm so happy, seriously, we should...
増やしてこう、増やしてこう、増やしてこう、これからね。
increase it, let's increase it, let's increase it from now on.
前回はさ、シークレットベース歌ったよね。
Last time, you know, we sang "Secret Base."
歌ったね！嫉妬にしたさ、すげえの曲だけどさ、今回マジめちゃめちゃ元気じゃん。
We sang it! Though that was an amazing song, this time we're super energetic, right?
めっちゃ可愛かった！ブーブー好きだから、ブーブー！ブーブー！
It was super cute! I love "Boo Boo," so Boo Boo! Boo Boo!
そうね、いいよね、好き。
That's right, it's good, I love it.
可愛いよね。ねえ、イラストもさ、可愛いよね。
It's so cute. And you know, the illustration is cute too.
めちゃくちゃ綺麗だった、バッグのとかさ。そうそう、やばいよね、イラストね。見てなかった人、ダンスしか見てなかった人に、あ！ほら！
It was so gorgeous, like the background and stuff. Yeah, exactly, the illustration is insane. For those who didn't see it, who only watched the dance, ah! Look!
ほら見て見て！超可愛い！マジ超可愛い！イラストやばい、しかも下にもさ、映ってるんだよね。そうだよ。
Look, look! Super cute! Seriously super cute! The illustration is amazing, and plus, it's reflected on the bottom too, right? That's right.
行こう。反射しててもめっちゃ可愛いんだよ。そうそうそう、めっちゃ綺麗でね。
Let's go. Even with the reflection, it's super cute. Yeah, exactly, and it's super pretty.
やばいよな。ねえ、そうなんだよ。いい！めちゃめちゃいいよね。
It's crazy, right? Yeah, exactly. Great! It's so, so good.
超嬉しい！ステージも可愛いよね。
I'm so happy! The stage is cute too.
見てみて。え？そう。しょ...なんでもない。なんだよ。
Look at this. Huh? Yeah. Sh- ...it's nothing. What is that?
なんだよ。いや、初号機色っていう。
What is that? Well, it's Unit-1 colors, you could say.
え、じゃあさ、ちょっとしょ、ちょっと待って、しょ、ねねねねね、間違えちゃった、間違えちゃった。何何何。だって一人で、あれ一人でポーズしてたの、お一人で、お前だけ。
Uh, then, hey, wait a sec, Shi-, hey hey hey hey hey, I messed up, I messed up. What what what. Because you were posing by yourself, all alone, just you.
いやだからさ、可愛いね、あの言葉より、あの、体が語り。なるほどね、なるほどね。いつもの笑い癖が。
I mean, so, cute, you know, rather than words, your body speaks. I see, I see. Your usual laughing habit is...
あのさ、さっきさ、しおん先輩さ、なんか一人でお祝いしたり寂しそうだったからさ、え、ちょっとお祝いしてもいい？
You know, earlier, Shion-senpai looked kind of lonely celebrating by herself, so, uh, can I celebrate with you?
そうだよ、一人で。え、お祝いしてくれるの？え、いいの？え、本当？
That's right, all alone. Eh, you'll celebrate for me? Eh, really? Eh, really?
えじゃあ、ちょっと、ちょ、ちょっと待って、持ってくるわ。
Eh then, wait a sec, wait a sec, I'll go get it.
え、ちょっと持ってきって、持ってくる、待ってる、待ってるよ。裏ダンス。
Eh, wait, I can bring it, wait, wait, I'm waiting. Backstage dance.
じゃん！お待たせ！じゃーん！これ！百均でさ、買ったんだよ、クラッカー。
Tada! Thanks for waiting! Ta-da! This! I bought this at the 100-yen shop, a cracker.
ほら、見ててよ。なんか、いざもちょうだいよ。一人で寂しいんだから。
Look, watch. Like, give me some too. I'm lonely all by myself.
しおん先輩、本当にお誕生日おめでとうございます！やったー！ありがとう！
Shion-senpai, happy birthday to you! Yay! Thank you!
めちゃめちゃ飛んできてるよ！ありがと！嬉しい！おめでとうおめでとう！めちゃめちゃ飛んできてるよ！寂しさ吹き飛ばして、ありがとう！
It's flying right at me! Thank you! I'm so happy! Congratulations! It's flying all over! Blasting away the loneliness, thank you!
いや嬉しいな、いっぱい祝ってもらえるんだ、今日は。しょこ二人でお祝いだよ。
I'm so happy to be celebrated so much today. Shoko, we're celebrating together.
やった。もう寂しくない。
Yay. I'm not lonely anymore.
もう寂しくないね、よかった。もうこれで誕生日はみんなで過ごしたっていう思い出ができたし、るしあちゃんにクラッカーをしててもらったっていう思い出ができたよ。
I'm not lonely anymore, I'm glad. Now I have the memory of spending my birthday with everyone, and the memory of Rushia-chan popping a cracker for me.
え、そう？うん、ありがとう。泣きそうになった、急に泣きそうになった。
Eh, really? Yeah, thanks. I almost cried, suddenly I almost cried.
えじゃあさ、じゃあさ、せっかくだからさ、記念撮影しようよ。え、撮ろうよ。ね、撮ろう撮ろう、ねえ、撮ってもらおうこれ。
Eh then, since we have the chance, let's take a commemorative photo. Eh, let's take one. Hey, let's take one, hey, let's have someone take it.
ちょっとクラッカー置いてくね。うん、待ってる待ってる。裏ダンスして待ってる。
I'll put the cracker down. Yeah, waiting, waiting. I'm waiting doing a backstage dance.
あのさ、ぶーぶーのポーズ取りたい、さっきの。あ、いいね！やりずい、一番いいやつだったからさ、レトロだよあれ。近くにしよう、近くにしよう。
You know, I want to do the "boo-boo" pose from earlier. Ah, nice! It was the best one, so it's retro. Let's get close, let's get close.
ぶーぶー！ぶーぶー！やったー！やったー！
Boo-boo! Boo-boo! Yay! Yay!
どうだ？撮った？みんな。撮ったかな？
How was that? Did you take it? Everyone. Did you take it?
いいね！ぶーぶー、ぶーぶー。いや、可愛いんじゃないの？
Nice! Boo-boo, boo-boo. Hey, isn't it cute?
ねえ、いいんじゃないの？
Hey, isn't it good?
え、しおん先輩、何撮りたい？他に。え、そうそう、さっきさ、ね、いっぱいゲストがいたんだけどさ、みんなさ、ウサギのポーズしたからさ、ウサギやろう、ウサギ。
Eh, Shion-senpai, what else do you want to take? Eh, yeah, earlier, you know, we had a lot of guests, and everyone did the rabbit pose, so let's do the rabbit, the rabbit.
お、やるやる、うさぎやろう、ペコペコ。うさぎペコペコ。
Oh, let's do it, let's do the rabbit, peko-peko. Rabbit peko-peko.
こんぺこ、こんぺこ、こんぺこ！こんぺこ！
Konpeko, konpeko, konpeko! Konpeko!
どうだ？うさぎになってるかな？うさぎ？うさぎ跳びもしとく？うさぎ跳びしとこう。
How's that? Are we rabbits? Rabbit? Should we also do rabbit jumps? Let's do rabbit jumps.
えい、うさぎピョンピョン！ほら、もうすごいリアルだよこれ。ピョンピョン！いいじゃん！いいんじゃないの？
Ei, rabbit pyon-pyon! Look, it's super realistic. Pyon-pyon! That's nice! Isn't it good?
あとなんかあるかな？ないかな？ねえ、疲れちゃってるじゃん。疲れちゃってるじゃん、大丈夫？
And is there anything else? Is there? Hey, you look exhausted. You're exhausted, are you okay?
いやダンスしたあとだからさ、ちょっと疲れちゃった。
Well, since we just danced, I got a bit tired.
え、最後にさ、最後にちょっとやりたいことある。え、魔法使いたい、魔法！
Eh, lastly, there's something I want to do at the end. Eh, I want to use magic, magic!
魔法して魔法、魔法！え、ちょっとさ、行こうよ、しおんちゃん、ちょっと。行こうよ！
Do magic, magic, magic! Eh, come on, Shion-chan, let's go. Let's go!
おお、魔法使って！行こうよ！ふぁ！ふぁ！ほら、座る前にね、座る前にだよ。
Oh, use magic! Let's go! Fwa! Fwa! Look, before sitting down, before sitting down.
え、なんで？なんで？なんで？おちろ！うわ！
Eh, why? Why? Why? Fall down! Whoa!
ごめんね！ねえ、しおん先輩！ごめんね！ごめんね！ごめんね！もう！
Sorry! Hey, Shion-senpai! Sorry! Sorry! Sorry! Jeez!
楽しかった！ありがとう！誕生日だからって甘えてんな！
That was fun! Thank you! Don't take advantage just because it's your birthday!
え、じゃあさ、そろそろさ、お別れの時間?
Um, so, is it almost time to say goodbye?
ああ、寂しい。帰んない。
Ah, I'm sad. I'm not going home.
まだ遊ぶね?
We're still going to play, right?
いや、まだ遊ぶね?
We're still going to play!
うん。
Yeah.
まだ来るね?10秒後くらいに。
You'll come back again, right? In like 10 seconds.
早すぎ?
Way too fast!
また待ってるから!
I'll be waiting again!
ありがとう!
Thank you!
お誕生日おめでとう!バイバイ!バイバイ!ありがとう!ブー!
Happy, happy birthday! Bye-bye! Bye-bye! Thank you! Boo!
しかも行かないと。
Plus, I gotta go.
ああ、恋の定義がわからない
Ah, I don't know the definition of love,
まずスキップって基準もわからない
and I don't even know the basic criteria.
要は、恋してるときが恋しい
The point is, I miss you when I'm in love.
客観? 主観? エビデンスプリーズ!
Objective? Subjective? Evidence, please!
愛は計算じゃ解けない
Love can't be solved with calculations,
まず普通の計算も解けない
and first of all, normal math can't be solved either.
要はそんな状態が愛らしい
The point is, that kind of state is adorable.
アイノウ? ユーノウ?
I know? You know?
もう大抵の事象においてQがあってAを出して解けるのに
Even though most phenomena have a Q, give an A, and get solved,
勘違いって間違って解のないこの気持ちはなんだろう
misunderstandings and mistakes—what is this feeling with no solution?
DAZING!! モーションは相対性にステイ
DAZING!! Motion stays relative.
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love: a mellow tune we can't solve even while gazing at each other.
ワットイズラブ いま 1 2 3 で明かそうか
What is Love? Let's reveal it now in 1, 2, 3.
言葉で生み出すクエストョン (クエストョン!)
Questions born from words (Questions!)
ハートで高鳴るアンサー (アンサー!)
Answers throbbing in our hearts (Answers!)
測ったって不確実性 ぼくらの BPM
Measured uncertainty: our BPM.
チューリングラブ 宙に舞ったって信じないけど
Turing Love: even if we danced in the skies, I wouldn't believe it, but
フォーリンラブ 今は abc すらバグりそうだ
Falling Love: right now even ABC seems like it's gonna bug out.
なんでか教えてオイラー (オイラー!)
Tell me why, Euler (Euler!)
感想聞かせてフェルマー (フェルマー!)
Let me hear your thoughts, Fermat (Fermat!)
予測不可能性 今触れてみる
Unpredictability: let's touch upon it now.
さあ証明しよう (証明しよう)
Come on, let's prove it (Let's prove it)
間違いのないように
So there's no mistake.
証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it (Let's prove it)
この感情全部全部
All, all of these emotions.
証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it (Let's prove it)
正解があるなら
If there's a correct answer,
証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it (Let's prove it)
シンプルな Q.E.D.
A simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい! (したい!) 目に見えない無理難題を
Today of all days, I want to prove it! (Want to!) Invisible, impossible problems
ASAP! 導き出したい たどり着きたい 最適解へ
ASAP! I want to lead it out, reach the optimal solution.
何度空回ったってぶつかっちゃったって不可思議なこのアノマリーを
No matter how many times we spin our wheels or clash, this mysterious anomaly—
解き明かす過程さえ必要条件です
even the process of solving it is a necessary condition.
「3次元 (立体) における 2点 ab 間の 距離 を求めよ 。」
"Find the distance between two points a and b in 3D space."
的な 感じ だ と 思って た のに 表も公式も見当たらないし
I thought it would be something like that, but neither formulas nor tables are in sight,
参考資料にも載っていないから君と生み出してみせたいじゃん
and it's not in the reference materials either, so I want to create it together with you.
3次元 (世界) における この気持ちの求め方
How to calculate this feeling in a 3D (world)—
○だって×だって不安とってイコールで
circle or cross, taking away anxiety, equals...
近くなって遠くなって揺れるこの気持ちの針も
Getting closer, getting farther, the needle of these swaying feelings too—
(条件は明瞭) steppin'!!
(Conditions are clear) steppin'!!
エモーションは相愛性ミステイク
Emotion is a mutual love mistake.
チューリングラブ 騒ぎ出した胸脱ぎいたくなるほど
Turing Love: so much that my starting-to-race chest makes me want to strip it bare.
証明は 今も 角度 増して いる ようだ
Proof seems to be increasing its angle even now.
曖昧も除外して最大の仮説を 今、ふたりなら実証できそう
Excluding ambiguity too, with the greatest hypothesis, right now the two of us can likely demonstrate it.
チューリングラブ 見つめあったってきりないめろう (メロウ)
Turing Love: a mellow tune we can't solve even while gazing at each other (mellow)
ワットイズラブ いま 1 2 3 で明かそうか (明かそうか)
What is Love? Let's reveal it now in 1, 2, 3 (reveal it)
言葉で生み出すクエストョン (クエストョン!)
Questions born from words (Questions!)
ハートで高鳴るアンサー (アンサー!)
Answers throbbing in our hearts (Answers!)
測ったって不確実性 ぼくらの BPM
Measured uncertainty: our BPM.
チューリングラブ 宙に舞ったってその因果も
Turing Love: even if we danced in the skies, that karma too—
フォーリンラブ 今は xyz まで解りそうだ
Falling Love: right now it seems we can solve it all the way to XYZ.
確かめさせてピタゴラス (ピタゴラス!)
Let me verify, Pythagoras (Pythagoras!)
確かめさせてリーマン (リーマン!)
Let me verify, Riemann (Riemann!)
予測済み可変性 今触れてみる
Pre-calculated variability: let's touch upon it now.
さあ証明しよう (証明しよう)
Come on, let's prove it (Let's prove it)
間違いのないように
So there's no mistake.
証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it (Let's prove it)
この感情全部全部
All, all of these emotions.
証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it (Let's prove it)
正解があるなら
If there's a correct answer,
証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it (Let's prove it)
推測を超えて!
Beyond conjecture!
証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it (Let's prove it)
間違いのないように
So there's no mistake.
証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it (Let's prove it)
この感情全部全部
All, all of these emotions.
証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it (Let's prove it)
正解があるなら
If there's a correct answer,
証明しよう (証明しよう)
Let's prove it (Let's prove it)
シンプルな Q.E.D.
A simple Q.E.D.
イェーイ!おめでとう!よかった!
Yay! Congratulations! Great job!
シオンちゃんはなんちゃいになっちゃいの?
How old is Shion-chan turning?
いっちゃい!
"One year old!"
さすがに一歳じゃない、ちょっと
As if you're one year old, come on.
一歳よ、さすがに。
You're one, seriously.
もうちょっとね、いいライン攻めないと。
You gotta aim for a better line than that.
35歳!
35 years old!
攻めたな。
You went bold.
結婚しようね、お互い。
Let's get married, both of us.
え、結構いい歳だからさ、やっぱり。
Well, we're at a pretty good age, so after all...
記念撮影とろ?え、誕生日プレゼントとしてさ、記念撮影とろ?
Let's take a commemorative photo? As a birthday present, let's take a photo?
記念撮影とろ?
Let's take a photo?
婚約あの結婚のさ。
Engagement... like marriage...
あら。
Oh my.
婚約指輪とかないの?ねえねえねえ!
Don't you have an engagement ring or anything? Hey hey hey!
チーズ!
Cheese!
かわいい～
So cute~
じゃあさ、あのチューリングラブのイラストと同じようなポーズ、ちょっとイラスト撮ってみよっか
Shall we pose just like the illustrations in Turing Love?
どうかな？来るかな？
I wonder. Will it appear?
あ、来た来た来た！
Ah, it's here, it's here!
じゃあ、ちょっとかっこいいな。ちょっとかっこよすぎじゃない？
Isn't this a bit too cool?
シオ、かっこいいね、なんか。
Shion, you look cool. Somehow.
かっこよすぎじゃん。おー、可愛い！かっこいい、なんか顔かっこいい！
It's way too cool! Oh, cute! Your face is cool!
じゃあ後ろ。せーので振り返るよ。うん。せーのっ
Okay, backward. We'll turn around on three. Ready, go.
あれ？気のせい？
Huh? My imagination?
気のせいだよ、気のせい。
Just your imagination.
気のせいか。
Oh, right.
はい！イエーイ！みんな撮って写真！
Okay! Yay! Everyone take a picture!
あ、おかゆのフラスコにおにぎり入ってるよ。
Ah, there's a rice ball in Okayu's flask.
ちょ、待ってシオン、それどころじゃないよ。
Wait, Shion, this is no time for that!
それどころじゃないな、ほら。行こ。
This is no time for that, look. Let's go.
せーのっ
Ready, set—
あーーー！しおっころだーー！かわいいーー！
Ahhh! It's Shiokoro! So cute!
しおっころとおかゆの子だね、これ。かわいいね！
It's a child of Shiokoro and Okayu. Cute!
いやちょっとこれ貰っていいですか？しおっころ。
Um, can I have this, Shiokoro?
ちょ、待って待って！だめだよ！あげないよ！
Wait, wait! No way! I won't give it to you!
可愛いね！可愛い！
So cute! Cute!
あげない！めちゃめちゃ可愛い！写真撮ろう、写真撮ろうか一緒に。
I won't give it! It's super cute! Let's take a picture together!
貰っていい、後で可愛い。あげない！あげない！
Can I have it later? Cute! I won't give it!
これ近いなこいつ。かわいい。おめめもぱちぱちしてる。
This guy is pretty close. Cute. Its eyes are blinking too.
ちっちゃいな結構ね。ちっちゃ。どこ行っちゃうの？
So small, isn't it? Where are you going?
でっかくのっと…おまえ、成長するのか？成長だ、成長。
It's huge... Hey, do you grow? Growth, growth.
んなおっきいしおっころ見たことない。
I've never seen such a big Shiokoro.
かわいい。遊園地とかにいるやつだね、これ。
Cute. It's the kind of thing you see at amusement parks.
マスコットキャラ。かわいい。かわいい。かわいすぎる。
Mascot character. Cute. Cute. Too cute.
シオンの魔法でさ、小さくなるのかな、もしかして。
Maybe it gets smaller with Shion's magic?
あ、そうするか。じゃあ、小さくなーれ！
Ah, let's do that. Then, become small!
おおーーー！小さっ！めめちっちゃ！
Oooh! So small! It's tiny!
しおっころ！
Shiokoro!
じゃあね。バイバイ。
See you. Bye-bye.
パーンってやったら消えるのかな。パーン！あ、帰っちゃった。帰っちゃった。
Will it disappear if I go 'bang'? Ah, it went home.
結婚できたね。子供も生まれちゃった。
We got married. We even had a child.
そうかね。そろそろ結婚の時間だよ。
Is that so? It's almost time for marriage.
あ、そうか！いくかじゃあ。行こっか。
Oh, right! Shall we go then?
はい、というわけで、ゲストの皆さん、本当にありがとうございました。
Hi, everyone. Thank you so much to our guests.
今日は誕生日祝って頂けて最高の誕生日になった。
Having my birthday celebrated made it the best birthday ever.
本当にね、うれしかった。まじでありがとう。
I'm truly happy. Seriously, thank you.
見てくれたみんなもありがとう。
Thank you to everyone who watched too.
ここからも本番みたいな、ここからも本番みたいな感じで告知したいと思います。
From here on, I'd like to make some announcements like the real show is starting now.
いぇい！いっぱいいあるからね、最後までみんながさに見てってください。
There are a lot of things, so please keep watching until the very end.
まず、紫咲シオン誕生日記念2021グッズ販売します。いぇい！
So first, we are selling Murasaki Shion Birthday Commemoration 2021 goods. Yay!
まずは、こちら！誕生日記念フルセット！いぇい！はい、めちゃめちゃ可愛い。
So first, here! The full birthday set! Yay! Yes, it's super cute.
まず見て貰った通りめちゃめちゃ可愛いんですけど
As you saw, it's super cute, but—
なんと、記念グッズ3点と、箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカード、Tam-U先生描き下ろしのポストカードがついてきます。
It comes with 3 commemoration goods and a hot-foil stamped message postcard by Tam-U!
ポストカードのイラストとおっぱいマウスパッドのイラストがちょっと違うんだよね。
The postcard illustration and the oppai mousepad illustration are a little different.
おっぱいマウスパッドのイラストの方はね、猫耳がないんだけど、ポストカードの方はね猫耳でちょっと。
On the oppai mousepad she has no cat ears, but on the postcard she does.
なんてエッチな、エッチなポーズをしております。
Doing such a lewd pose!
おっぱいマウスパッド出したがったんだよね本当。みんなの手首が疲れないからね。
I really wanted to release an oppai mousepad. Your wrists won't get tired from now on.
パソコン作業してる方、ゲームする方、どうぞよかったら買ってね。
If you're working on a PC or playing games, please buy one if you'd like.
そして、あとは缶バッチ！と、ランダム缶バッチ(全4種)！前回アクキーやったんだけど今回は缶バッチになっております。
And then, badges! Random badge (4 types)! Last time we did keychains, but this time it's badges.
めちゃめちゃ可愛い！4種類、全4種類でランダムで出てきます。なもり先生の描き下ろしと...
Super cute! 4 types in total, coming randomly. Illustrated by Namori-sensei.
おります！
We have them!
まじ可愛い！本当に！
Seriously cute! Really!
ぜひね、あの全種で集めたい方は単品購入も、
If you want to collect the whole set,
単品の購入もありますので、ぜひよろしくお願いします。
individual items are available, so please check them out!
えっと買うと、セットだと、
If you buy the set,
あの1個しか届かないからね、全部欲しい方はあの、
because you only get one, if you want all of them...
頑張ってください(笑)
Good luck getting them all!
はい、そして次！
Yes, and next!
塩っ子ぬいぐるみ！
Shiokko plushie!
イェーイ！
Yay!
これは、あのー、ここにもね、ちょっとちらみ、ちらみしてるけど、
This is peeking over here a bit,
こいつ！こいつのぬいぐるみになります！
It's a plushie of this guy!
今日みんながね、あのステージにいたのと同じ、同じのぬいぐるみです！
It's a plushie just like the one on stage today!
あ、可愛い！本当に。
Ah, cute! Really!
ちょっとでかいんだよ。結構でかい感じの
It's a bit big. Quite a large...
大きさ？ぬいぐるみのおっきさ結構大きいでしょ？
The plushie size is pretty big, right?
30cmだから。
It's 30cm.
こんぐら、30cmってどんぐらい？
About 30cm, how big is that?
こんぐら、こんぐらい？わかんないけど
About this big? I don't know, but...
なってます！めちゃめちゃね結構存在感があるからね、あの、
It has a huge presence, so everyone,
みんなよかったら買ってくだい。
please buy it if you'd like.
あの、10個ぐらい買ってね、部屋の床に敷き詰めて。
Buy about 10 and line them up on your floor.
はい、ということでこれがね全部セットです。単品での購入もあるからね、よかったら買って買ってくださーい！
So that's the whole set! Individual purchases are available too, so please buy them!
はい、次、ドドン！
Yes, next, dodon!
第2告知！ドドン！
2nd announcement! Dodon!
はい、なんとLINEスタンプが出ます！イェーイ！
LINE stamps are coming out! Yay!
紫咲シオンのLINEスタンプです！
Murasaki Shion's LINE stamps!
え、こちらはですね、むーらん先生描きおろしのLINEスタンプとなっております！24個かな？LINEスタンプで24個だよね？
These are LINE stamps newly illustrated by Moolan-sensei! 24 of them, right?
めちゃめちゃ可愛いからね、全部。ショップのお気に入りはですね、あの、あれ！
They're all super cute! My favorite is...
ビーム出してるやつかな？ビーム出してるやつ。
the one shooting a beam! The one shooting a beam.
ビーム出すやつ。わーって出すやつ。これめちゃ好き。
The one that goes "whoosh"! I love it.
あと寝坊のやつね、「寝坊します。」
Also the oversleeping one. "I overslept."
「寝坊します。」二度寝しますと、
"I overslept." If you hit snooze,
ちょっと遅れます。これは自分用。
you'll be a bit late. This is for personal use.
これ自分用ですね。これマジみんな使ってほしい会社とかに。
I really want everyone to use this at work.
会社のの上司とかのLINEに使ってほしい。「二度寝します。」
Use it on your boss's LINE. "I'm going back to sleep."
「で今日休もう。」
"So I'll take today off."
というわけで、こちらはですね、この後発売されるので、よかったら手に入れてください。いっぱい押してほしい。マジでポンポンポンポン、土下座にしたばくしよう。
So, these will be released soon, so please get them if you'd like. Please spam them!
はい、次！ドドン！はい、フォニーのね歌ってみたがこの後、えーこの配信の終わったあとすぐに上がります。22:00かな？お,上がり上がる予定です。
Yes, my cover of "Phony" will be released right after this stream ends, around 22:00.
この配信の終わったあとすぐにね、みんな見てください。いっぱい聞いてね。フォニー、フォニー、フォニー、いっぱい聞いてね。
Right after this stream ends, everyone please check it out. Listen to it a lot!
そして最後です！最後なんですけど、明日の12月9日に誕生日アクセサリのお披露目があります！
And finally! Tomorrow on December 9th, there'll be a reveal of my birthday accessories!
めちゃめちゃ可愛いからね、本当によかったら見てください。絶対です。明日もどうぞよろしくお願いします、引き続き。
They're super cute, so please check it out. See you tomorrow!
裏のほうばっか見てないで
Don't just look at the back side,
うらぱぱぱパラリラ踊れよ
Urā papapa pararira, dance!
骸学校の誘導で
Led by the skeletal school,
艶やかな我儘称えよ
Praise our glamorous selfishness!
いないいないばあでこっち向いて
Peek-a-boo, look over here,
萎たから未来を探せよ
Search for a withered future!
次第愛待って高まって
Gradually longing, heightening,
ぱたぱたぱわ放て黒魔術
Patapata power, unleash black magic!
星の奥に集えよ
Gather deep within the stars,
闇に震え上がるデロス
Deros trembling in the dark!
切っ首に響く言葉が
Words echoing on the severed neck,
ぶち切れハートよパラダイス
Snap your heart, paradise!
嫌いここをくそまで届け
Hateful heart, reach all the way there,
これからも私の元で
From now on, by my side!
不思議の力打ち放て
Unleash mysterious powers,
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
Making even the world smile!
うらぱぱぱパラリラ歌えば
Sing urā papapa pararira,
一生一緒だよね
We'll be together forever, right?
暗い門だか知ってないで
Don't just know it's a dark gate,
萎たからださらば踊れよ
Withered body, farewell and dance!
視界外名いらすらないで
Don't even name outside the field of view,
今はただ離れて叶えて
Now just leave and make it come true!
やや待ってあっち向いて
Wait a bit, look that way,
今はまだ心の準備を
Still preparing my heart!
期待裂き切って固まって
Expectation torn and solidified,
ぱたぱたぱわ動け黒魔術
Patapata power, move black magic!
われに続け今宵の
Follow me tonight,
闇を破れメシアよ
Break the darkness, Messiah!
打つべきものその名は
The one to strike, its name is
眠りの発祥パラダイス
The paradise of slumber's origin!
暗い方ばっか見ないで
Don't just look at the dark side,
ウラッパッパッパ パラリラ 踊れよ
Ura-pappappa paralira, dance!
魔界学校の優等生
The honor student of the demon academy,
華やかな我が魔力讃えよ
Praise my dazzling magic power!
イナイイナイばぁ！でこっち向いて
Peek-a-boo! Now look this way,
したたかな未来を咲かせよ
Make a resilient future bloom!
次第相場って高まった
Our market value rose higher,
溜め込んだmp放て黒魔術
Release stored MP with dark magic!
ウラッパッパッパ パラリラ 歌えば
Sing along with ura-pappappa paralira,
一生 一緒 頑張れ
We'll do our best together forever!
ひらりひらりきらり紫に染まって
Fluttering and glittering, dyed in purple,
これからもあなたの元で
Continuing to be by your side from now on,
奇跡の呪文解き放って
Unleashing the spell of miracles,
咲かせうる笑顔の花を
Making the flower of smiles bloom!
暗い方ばっか見ないで
Don't just look at the dark side,
これからも変わらないままで
Remaining unchanged from now on as well,
不思議な力ほら宿って
Look, mysterious power dwells within,
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
Making the whole world smile too!
ウラッパッパッパ パラリラ 歌えば
Sing along with ura-pappappa paralira,
一生 一緒 だよね？
We'll be together forever, right?
絶対 一緒 だよね？
Definitely together forever, right?